<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Guides - NETMIKO.COM</title>
	<atom:link href="https://netmiko.com/category/guides/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://netmiko.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 12:01:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://netmiko.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/favicon-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Guides - NETMIKO.COM</title>
	<link>https://netmiko.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>[ Beginners Guide ] A Guide to Spotify</title>
		<link>https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-a-guide-to-spotify/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AOMIE]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 11:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://netmiko.com/?p=6142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple guide to Spotify App, in this guide I will be teaching you the things you need to know about Spotify, like how you can use it, install it or how you can access different features and stuff, etc. The guide is small but very helpful to you if you read it &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-a-guide-to-spotify/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">[ Beginners Guide ] A Guide to Spotify</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
The post <a href="https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-a-guide-to-spotify/">[ Beginners Guide ] A Guide to Spotify</a> appeared first on <a href="https://netmiko.com">NETMIKO.COM</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple guide to Spotify App, in this guide I will be teaching you the things you need to know about Spotify, like how you can use it, install it or how you can access different features and stuff, etc.</p>



<p>The guide is small but very helpful to you if you read it thoroughly. So lets begin, now first lets know what Spotify is.</p>



<h2>What is Spotify</h2>



<p>Spotify is a music streaming service that provides users with unlimited access to over 30 million songs. The service is available in most of the world and offers users a variety of different ways to listen to their favorite artists, from albums and curated playlists, to individual songs. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://netmiko.files.wordpress.com/2022/06/sh.jpg" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Spotify also offers podcasts and video content, as well as artist-specific pages where they can post photos, videos, and other media.</p>



<p>Spotify was founded in 2006 by Swedish entrepreneurs Daniel Ek and Martin Lorentzon. The company has since grown into one of the most popular music streaming services in the world with more than 140 million active monthly users. Spotify operates under a freemium model: basic features are free for all.</p>



<h2>What is Spotify Premium</h2>



<p>Now the Spotify service runs on a freemium model, which means it gives people free access to some features of their app and limits access to some other features.</p>



<p>On the regular Spotify app you can listen to songs with ads playing in between the songs, also you get a limit of how many songs you can skip. It also prevents you from downloading songs to your offline storage for offline listening.</p>



<p>Now what Spotify Premium offers is ad-free, on-demand access to the largest music library in the world.</p>



<p>The service is available for a monthly fee of $9.99, and for an additional $4.99 users can use Spotify&#8217;s mobile app without ads, download songs for offline listening, and listen to music without interruption from advertisements.</p>



<h2>Features of Spotify</h2>



<p><strong>1. High Quality Songs</strong> &#8211; Spotify has very high quality songs that you can listen to. Now the quality of the songs also depends on the version of Spotify you have, like the premium version has much higher quality compared to free version.</p>



<p><strong>2. Song &amp; Playlist Search</strong> &#8211; On Spotify you can search for individual songs or you can search for playlists made by both individual users and Spotify. You can also search for podcasts that are available on Spotify..</p>



<p><strong>3. Library</strong> &#8211; You can like songs and those will be added to your liked songs in library, you can also save playlists and podcasts in your library.</p>



<p><strong>4. Radio</strong> &#8211; Liked a song and want to listen to more songs like that??? Then you can use the &#8216;Go to song Radio&#8217; option to play similar songs to a song you want. To do this just click on the three dots of the song you want, after that click the &#8216; Go to Song Radio &#8216; option.</p>



<p><strong>5. Lyrics</strong> &#8211; By default the lyrics of the song that is currently playing a displayed at the bottom of the song. So if you want to sing along then you can do that using Spotify without searching for YouTube videos.</p>



<p><strong>6. Downloading Songs</strong> &#8211; You can download songs you like to your device which you can play later when you are not connected to the internet.</p>



<p>Now there are lots of different features in Spotify, but the ones I talked about above are the basic ones you need to know.</p>



<h2>How to Install Spotify</h2>



<p>To install Spotify in your mobile device or on your pc you can download it from playstore, app store, or windows store or you can download its apk file. The link for the app is below &#8211; </p>



<div class="dt" dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">

<center>
<span id="countdown">You have to wait 15 seconds.</span></center>
<br>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<b>Download Spotify from Here</b><br>
<a href="https://aomie.in/netmiko/spotify.html" id="download_link" style="display: none;"><img src="https://netmiko.files.wordpress.com/2022/06/da.jpg"></a>
<noscript>JavaScript needs to be enabled in order to be able to download.</noscript>
<script type="application/javascript">
(function(){
   var message = "%d seconds before download link appears";
   // seconds before download link becomes visible
   var count = 15;
   var countdown_element = document.getElementById("countdown");
   var download_link = document.getElementById("download_link");
   var timer = setInterval(function(){
      // if countdown equals 0, the next condition will evaluate to false and the else-construct will be executed
      if (count) {
          // display text
          countdown_element.innerHTML = "You have to wait %d seconds.".replace("%d", count);
          // decrease counter
          count--;
      } else {
          // stop timer
          clearInterval(timer);
          // hide countdown
          countdown_element.style.display = "none";
          // show download link
          download_link.style.display = "";
      }
   }, 1000);
})();
</script>
</div>

</div>



<p>Installation requires you to have a little bit of storage empty so make sure you have that.</p>



<h2>How to Use Spotify</h2>



<p>Using Spotify is very easy , after you have installed it you need to open the app, here you need to create a Spotify account using your Gmail or mobile number.</p>



<p>After creating the account you will need to pick a few artist that you like after which you can select the language you want to listen songs in and that&#8217;s it .  You will be greeted to the home page where you can now search for different songs, playlist, podcast etc. and enjoy your day.</p>



<p>If you want to get rid of the ads or the skip limit then you will need to upgrade to premium plan.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>And that&#8217;s it, and that was the small guide to Spotify.</p>The post <a href="https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-a-guide-to-spotify/">[ Beginners Guide ] A Guide to Spotify</a> appeared first on <a href="https://netmiko.com">NETMIKO.COM</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>[ Beginners Guide for Bitlife &#8211; Life Simulator ] Playing and Installation Guide</title>
		<link>https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-for-bitlife-life-simulator-playing-and-installation-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AOMIE]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://netmiko.com/?p=6115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple guide for Bitlife &#8211; Life Simulator. This guide will cover the basics of the game and will also show you the steps to install Bitlife on your own phone. What is Bitlife? Bitlife is a text-based life simulation game where you make different choices for different outcomes. It is developed by &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-for-bitlife-life-simulator-playing-and-installation-guide/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">[ Beginners Guide for Bitlife &#8211; Life Simulator ] Playing and Installation Guide</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
The post <a href="https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-for-bitlife-life-simulator-playing-and-installation-guide/">[ Beginners Guide for Bitlife – Life Simulator ] Playing and Installation Guide</a> appeared first on <a href="https://netmiko.com">NETMIKO.COM</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple guide for <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.candywriter.bitlife&amp;hl=en_IN&amp;gl=US">Bitlife &#8211; Life Simulator</a>. This guide will cover the basics of the game and will also show you the steps to install Bitlife on your own phone.</p>



<h2>What is Bitlife?</h2>



<p>Bitlife is a text-based life simulation game where you make different choices for different outcomes. It is developed by Candywriter, LLC who makes casual and fun applications for mobile devices and tablets, Candywriter LLC is based of US.</p>



<h2>How do we play Bitlife?</h2>



<p>Playing bitlife is fairly simple. As soon as you open the app you are greeted with screen from where you can start a new life, to do that just click on the &#8216;Start a New Life&#8217; button.</p>



<p>Now you can create two types of life, first one is a random life and second one is a custom life. So if you want a very random life then choose random, or if you want to add something to your life then choose custom. </p>



<p>As soon as you create a new life / character you will be born as a infant, aka you will be 0 years old. Now after the character id created you can see all the information about the character, like relationships, assets, activities etc.</p>



<p>You can see the names of your characters mother and father, their occupation and all other information. Now to continue the game you will need to click on the &#8216;Age&#8217; button, This will increase the age of your character. </p>



<p>As you age you will see different events that happened with you at the top of the screen. Now as you age you will get some random choices that you will need to select, now the choices you make will change how your future becomes, so choose wisely.</p>



<p>These choices appear randomly at random age.</p>



<h2>Activities and Relationship</h2>



<p>In Bitlife you get tons of things to do, like you can spend time with your family and friends, you can go do a job, you can go do some sports etc.</p>



<p>Its all like in real life, and the choices you make will enable or disable different things for you.</p>



<p>You can do activities and spend time with your family by clicking the relationship or the activities button at the bottom of the app.</p>



<h2>Future</h2>



<p>Whatever you do, whatever choices you pick will determine how your future is going to be. As you age you get different choices and different options to choose from.</p>



<p>Now it all depends on what you are going to choose, a life with just joy, adventure, work, or mix of all the different things.</p>



<h2>How to Install BitLife &#8211; Life Simulator?</h2>



<p>The installation process of Bitlife is very easy, now there are two ways that you can download bitlife. You can download it directly from your app store or playstore, or you can download its apk file that you can install.</p>



<div class="dt" dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">

<center>
<span id="countdown">You have to wait 15 seconds.</span></center>
<br>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<b>Download APK from Here</b><br>
<a href="https://cdn.ezjojoy.com/packages/com.candywriter.bitlife/BitLife_3.2.4_231_13c2a1.apk" id="download_link" style="display: none;"><img src="https://netmiko.files.wordpress.com/2022/06/da.jpg"></a>
<noscript>JavaScript needs to be enabled in order to be able to download.</noscript>
<script type="application/javascript">
(function(){
   var message = "%d seconds before download link appears";
   // seconds before download link becomes visible
   var count = 15;
   var countdown_element = document.getElementById("countdown");
   var download_link = document.getElementById("download_link");
   var timer = setInterval(function(){
      // if countdown equals 0, the next condition will evaluate to false and the else-construct will be executed
      if (count) {
          // display text
          countdown_element.innerHTML = "You have to wait %d seconds.".replace("%d", count);
          // decrease counter
          count--;
      } else {
          // stop timer
          clearInterval(timer);
          // hide countdown
          countdown_element.style.display = "none";
          // show download link
          download_link.style.display = "";
      }
   }, 1000);
})();
</script>
</div>

</div>



<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-buttons"></div>



<p>After you have downloaded the apk file, click on it and then click on the install option, if you are getting any sort of warning then its ok, just click on &#8216;ok&#8217; then proceed.</p>



<p>If you want to download from app store then here&#8217;s the link &#8211; <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.candywriter.bitlife">Android</a> |  <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bitlife-life-simulator/id1374403536">Apple</a></p>



<p>After installing bitlife open it and enjoy the game.</p>



<h2>How to Uninstall Bitlife?</h2>



<p>You can easily uninstall bitlife from your phone by going to settings then to app settings, in app settings search for bitlife and click it. After that you will get the uninstall option.</p>



<p>So that is how you can play or install bitlife.</p>The post <a href="https://netmiko.com/beginners-guide-for-bitlife-life-simulator-playing-and-installation-guide/">[ Beginners Guide for Bitlife – Life Simulator ] Playing and Installation Guide</a> appeared first on <a href="https://netmiko.com">NETMIKO.COM</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
